rtr.org 2012-12-31

# RTR.org - Privacy Policy

## Privacy Statement

_ Updated: November 1, 2010_

Thank you for visiting RTR.org (Restore the Republic)! RTR.org is the Action Network of the Revolution. RTR.org has created this network so that you could benefit from the community of Americans who feel that real change begins with individuals who work together with a foundation on Constitutional values. __  RTR.org and Restore the Republic (“We”) are committed to protecting the privacy of our members.

This policy describes the ways We collect, store, use and protect your personal information. You accept this policy when you sign up for or use our products, services or any other features, technologies or functionalities offered by us on our website or through any other means.

We may amend this policy at any time by posting a revised version on our website. The revised version will be effective at the time we post it.

## 1.     Collection and use of customer information

Your personal details will be collected and processed when you order, purchase, register, subscribe or make use of any of our products or services.

When you visit any of our websites, we also collect website usage information, and information about your computer and internet connection. This includes your computer's IP address, the type and version of browser and operating system you use, your internet domain and, if you visited via a link from another website, the URL of the linking page.

This information is collected to help us:

·         fulfill your order

·         manage your registration preferences

·         send you notifications

·         personalize web content and advertising based on your personal characteristics or preferences

·         ensure, as far as is practical, that our websites are compatible with the browsers and operating systems used by most of our visitors

·         conduct customer satisfaction surveys

And, if you allow us to, we may also:

·         tell you about additional products and services

·         invite you to participate in market research and surveys

If you do not wish to receive our promotional communications, you may opt-out from receiving these communications by clicking the opt-out link included at the bottom of every promotional message. 

You may not opt-out of receiving invoices and usage information, service announcements, and customer service communications, although they can deactivate their account.

We also use your information for in-house research and analysis. This helps us to:

·         improve our understanding of customer needs

·         create customer profiles

·         support strategic development

·         To enable us to conduct research we may share your information with third party suppliers employed to help. All results of any research and analysis will be anonymized or aggregated information and will not reveal any personal details of individual members.

## 2.     Cookies

A cookie is a small file which is placed on your hard drive when you visit our website. We use information from cookies for purposes which may include:

·         identifying returning users, registrants and subscribers

·         eliminating the need for returning users to re-enter their login details

·         enabling you to move more easily around our sites

·         tracking your use of our sites to better develop our sites in accordance with your requirements

·         building up an anonymous profile based on your browsing patterns across our sites and third party websites, which enables us to make advertisements and content available to you that is more relevant to your interests

You can delete cookies from your hard drive at any time. Bear in mind, though, that if you delete them, any settings such as your stored username and password will have to be reset when you next log in.

You will be able to use our websites even if your browser is not set to accept cookies. However, certain features and content may not be available to you and you will have to log in every time you visit.

## 3.     Third Party E-mail Service

We may use reputable third parties, like Aweber.com, to deliver the e-mails you receive if you have subscribed to e-mail newsletters, or have chosen to receive information about We products, services and offers. These third parties use unique identifiers and invisible images (often called "pixel tags" or "clear GIFs") to perform message open sensing, message format sensing, and click-through sensing in order to bring you more relevant information.

## 4.     Advertisements

From time to time We use third parties such as DoubleClick to deliver the advertisements displayed on our websites. DoubleClick may note some of the pages you visit through the use of pixel tags (also called "clear gifs"). In the course of serving advertisements to this site, DoubleClick may place or recognize a unique cookie on your computer in order to bring to you more relevant information and to make sure that you do not receive the same ad many times in the same session. Some of the advertisers on our sites do not use DoubleClick ad-serving software and their ads are served by third-parties who may also place cookies. you may choose to opt out of the DoubleClick cookie at any time by using [DoubleClick’s opt-out cookie](http://www.google.com/intl/en/privacy_ads.html).

## 5.     External links

Our websites may, from time to time, contain links to external sites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies or the content of such sites and we recommend that you read the privacy policies on any external sites you use.

## 6.     Transfer of personal data overseas

As the internet is a global environment, collecting and processing personal information may involve the transmission of this data internationally, including outside of the Unite States. Therefore, by communicating electronically with us you acknowledge and agree to your personal data being processed in this way.

## 7.     Children under 13

We do not intentionally collect any personal information from individuals under the age of 13. When necessary, underage users will be told not to submit any personal details and we will make every effort to delete any details of such users where a parent or guardian has informed us that these details have been collected.

## 8.     As a result of legal requirements

We may be required to provide personally identifiable information to comply with legally mandated reporting, disclosure or other legal process requirements. 

## 9.     Information security

We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. These include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, including appropriate encryption.

We restrict access to personal information to employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to process it on our behalf. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline if they fail to meet these obligations.

## Contact Information

We welcome your comments regarding this privacy statement. Contact us [ here](http://rtr.org/help/contact)!
